<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Rune Mage</name>
        <description>A magical class specializing in the drawing and infusing of runes to create enhancements.</description>
        <author>Custom</author>
        <update version="1.0.0">
            <file name="class-runemage.xml" url="https://github.com/eskerg/dnd/blob/main/class-runemage.xml"/> 
        </update>
    </info>
    <class>
        <name>Rune Mage</name>
        <hd>1d6</hd>
        <proficiency>Intelligence</proficiency>
        <proficiency>Wisdom</proficiency>
        <armorProficiency>
            <armor>Medium armor</armor>
        </armorProficiency>
        <weaponProficiency>
            <weapon>Runic Axe</weapon>
        </weaponProficiency>
        <skillChoices count="2">
            <skill>Arcana</skill>
            <skill>History</skill>
            <skill>Insight</skill>
            <skill>Investigation</skill>
            <skill>Religion</skill>
        </skillChoices>
        <equipment>
            <item>Runic Axe</item>
            <item>Medium Armor</item>
            <item>Explorer's Pack</item>
        </equipment>
        <feature>
            <name>Rune Drawing</name>
            <level>1</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 1st level, you can draw magical runes to create various effects. You start with three runes.
                <b>Rune of Protection:</b> Provides temporary hit points equal to 1d4 + Intelligence modifier for 1 hour.
                <b>Rune of Speed:</b> Increases the target's speed by 10 feet for 1 minute.
                <b>Rune of Blade:</b> Adds 1d4 damage to a weapon for 1 minute.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Rune Infusion</name>
            <level>2</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                Starting at 2nd level, you can infuse runes into items, granting them permanent effects. This process takes 1 hour and 50 gold per rune level.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Rune Mastery</name>
            <level>3</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 3rd level, choose a rune specialization: Protection, Power, or Transmutation.
                <b>Protection:</b> Gain the ability to draw the Runic Shield, adding +2 to AC for 10 minutes.
                <b>Power:</b> Gain the ability to draw the Runic Strike, adding 1d6 magical damage to a weapon for 10 minutes.
                <b>Transmutation:</b> Gain the ability to draw the Runic Transmutation, changing the material of an object for 1 hour.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
            <level>4</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At the 4th level and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score by 2 or two ability scores by 1. You cannot increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Greater Rune Drawing</name>
            <level>5</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 5th level, you can draw advanced runes. Choose two new runes from the advanced rune list.
                <b>Rune of Power:</b> Adds 1d6 magical damage.
                <b>Rune of Resistance:</b> Adds +1 AC and resistance to a damage type.
                <b>Rune of Speed:</b> Allows an additional attack as a bonus action.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Runic Empowerment</name>
            <level>6</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 6th level, your runes' effects last twice as long.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Runic Infusion Mastery</name>
            <level>7</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 7th level, you can infuse two runes into one item, combining their effects. This process takes an additional 2 hours and costs 50 more gold.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Greater Runic Smithing</name>
            <level>9</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 9th level, you can create advanced weapons and armor with more complex runic effects.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Master Rune Drawing</name>
            <level>10</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 10th level, you can draw master runes. Choose two from the master rune list.
                <b>Rune of Resurrection:</b> Allows the casting of Resurrection spell.
                <b>Rune of Transcendence:</b> Grants immunity to one damage type.
                <b>Rune of Mastery:</b> Doubles the duration and effect of any one rune.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
        <feature>
            <name>Ultimate Rune Craft</name>
            <level>20</level>
            <description><![CDATA[
                At 20th level, your mastery of runes reaches its peak. All runes you draw last indefinitely until dismissed, and you can draw up to three runes simultaneously on a single item or person.
            ]]></description>
        </feature>
    </class>
</elements>
